{
    "id": "cd850b1d7bfa48aa877473937c6f99af",
    "title": "Prepositions And Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I finished early ………………………. I worked fast.",
            "description": "Because is a conjunction. We use it to connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We were late ……………………….. the storm.",
            "description": "Because of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun.",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "because of"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… trying hard, she could not finish the job on time.",
            "description": "We use in spite of before an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "However",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. she tried hard, she could not finish the job on time.",
            "description": "Although is a conjunction. We use it to connect two clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "However",
                "In spite of",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. waking up early, I was late for work.",
            "description": "Despite and in spite of are interchangeable.",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "Despite",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………………… the fact that the government refuses to admit it, it has lost the support of the masses.",
            "description": "We cannot put a that-clause immediately after in spite of. Hence we introduce it with ‘the fact’.",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "In spite of",
                "However"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. the government refuses to admit it, its economic policy has failed time and again.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "However",
                "In spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I always take an umbrella ………………………… it rains.",
            "description": "After in case we usually use a present tense to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "in case",
                "if",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I wrote down his phone number ………………………. I should forget it.",
            "description": "Should + infinitive is very common after in case. It adds the meaning ‘by chance’.",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "because",
                "in case"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I wrote down his phone number …………………………. I might forget it.",
            "description": "Because I might forget it is similar to in case I should forget it.",
            "answers": [
                "in case",
                "if",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We will buy a chicken ………………………… we have guests.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "unless",
                "if",
                "in case of"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she is late, we will go ………………………. her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "unless",
                "without"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}